<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Anelia Milbrandt, NREL, Sr. Analyst</origin>
        <pubdate>20141030</pubdate>
        <title>SolidBiomass</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>This dataset contains information about the biomass resources generated by county in the United States. It includes the following feedstock categories: crop residues, forest residues, primary mill residues, secondary mill residues, and urban wood waste.</abstract>
      <purpose>The purpose of this dataset is to illustrate the solid biomass resources generated by county in the United States.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <rngdates>
          <begdate>20120620</begdate>
          <enddate>20120620</enddate>
        </rngdates>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Contiguous United States, Alaska and Hawaii</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-178.227822</westbc>
        <eastbc>-66.950005</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.390482</northbc>
        <southbc>18.910787</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>Biomass, biomass resource, solid biomass, crop residues, forest residues, primary mill residues, secondary mill residues, urban wood waste.</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>This GIS data was developed by the National Renewable Energy Laboratory ("NREL"), which is operated by the Alliance for Sustainable Energy, LLC for the U.S. Department of Energy ("DOE"). The user is granted the right, without any fee or cost, to use, copy, modify, alter, enhance and distribute this data for any purpose whatsoever, provided that this entire notice appears in all copies of the data. Further, the user of this data agrees to credit NREL in any publications or software that incorporate or use the data. Access to and use of the GIS data shall further impose the following obligations on the User. The names DOE/NREL may not be used in any advertising or publicity to endorse or promote any product or commercial entity using or incorporating the GIS data unless specific written authorization is obtained from DOE/NREL. The User also understands that DOE/NREL shall not be obligated to provide updates, support, consulting, training or assistance of any kind whatsoever with regard to the use of the GIS data. THE GIS DATA IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL DOE/NREL BE LIABLE FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO CLAIMS ASSOCIATED WITH THE LOSS OF DATA OR PROFITS, WHICH MAY RESULT FROM AN ACTION IN CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS CLAIM THAT ARISES OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE ACCESS OR USE OF THE GIS DATA. The User acknowledges that access to the GIS data is subject to U.S. Export laws and regulations and any use or transfer of the GIS data must be authorized under those regulations. The User shall not use, distribute, transfer, or transmit GIS data or any products incorporating the GIS data except in compliance with U.S. export regulations. If requested by DOE/NREL, the User agrees to sign written assurances and other export-related documentation as may be required to comply with U.S. export regulations.</useconst>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.0.3348</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>3141</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>8.983152841195215e-009</latres>
        <longres>8.983152841195215e-009</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 84</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>SolidBiomass</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Counties</enttypd>
        <enttypds>ESRI</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CNTY_NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>County name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE_NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State name</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>County FIPS</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CropRes</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field illustrates the harvesting crop residues from corn, wheat, soybeans, cotton, sorghum, barley, oats, rice, rye, canola, dry edible beans, peanuts, safflower, sunflower, sugarcane, and flaxseed by county. The crop residues are estimated using total crop production (data from USDA 2012 Census), crop to residue ratio, and moisture content. It is assumed that only 35% of the total residue could be collected as biomass. The remaining portion is to be left on the field to maintain ecological and agricultural functions. Data for 2012, in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NREL</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>UrbanWood</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field illustrates the urban wood waste by county - wood material from MSW (wood chips and pallets), utility tree trimming and/or private tree companies, and construction and demolition sites. Data for 2012, in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NREL</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SecMill</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field contains data for secondary mill residues by county (wood scraps and sawdust from woodworking shops — furniture factories, wood container and pallet mills, and wholesale lumberyards). Data for 2012, in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NREL</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ForestRes</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This category includes logging residues and other removable material left after carrying out silviculture operations and site conversions. Logging residue comprises unused portions of trees, cut or killed by logging and left in the woods. Other removables are the unutilized wood volume of trees cut or otherwise killed by cultural operations (e.g. pre-commercial thinnings) or land-clearings to non-forest uses. This data illustrates 65% of logging residues and 50% of other removals which is the portion that could be collected as biomass. The remaining portion is to be left on the field to maintain ecological functions. Source: USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database, 2012. Data in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PrimMill</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field contains data on primary mill residues by county. Primary mill residues include wood materials (coarse and fine) and bark generated at manufacturing plants (primary wood-using mills) when round wood products are processed into primary wood products, such as slabs, edgings, trimmings, sawdust, veneer clippings and cores, and pulp screenings. This data illustrates the total amount of primary mill residues (used and unused) by county. Note that most of this resource is currently utilized. Source: USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database, 2012. Data in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Total</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>This field combines all solid biomass resources by county: crop residues, forest residues, primary mill residues, secondary mill residues, and urban wood waste. Data for 2012, in dry metric tons/year.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NREL</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20141023</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>NREL</cntorg>
          <cntper>Anelia Milbrandt</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>Sr. Analyst</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
          <address>15013 Denver West Parkway</address>
          <city>Golden</city>
          <state>Colorado</state>
          <postal>80401</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>303-275-4633</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>Anelia.Milbrandt@nrel.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>